fultonbankonlinebnk.com 2015-12-07

# Fulton Financial Corporation

**About Us**

Fulton Financial Corporation (FFC) is a financial holding company headquartered in Lancaster, Pennsylvania. We are engaged, through our banking and other subsidiaries, in the business of providing financial services to customers located primarily in Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Maryland, Delaware and Virginia. FFC's banking subsidiaries include: Fulton Bank, N.A., Lancaster, Pennsylvania; Fulton Bank of New Jersey, Mount Laurel, New Jersey; FNB Bank, N.A., Danville, Pennsylvania; Lafayette Ambassador Bank, Easton, Pennsylvania; Swineford National Bank, Middleburg, Pennsylvania; The Columbia Bank, Columbia, Maryland. FFC's non-banking subsidiaries include: Fulton Life Insurance Company; Fulton Insurance Services Group, Inc.; Resource Service Corporation; Bankers Insurance, LLC. 

**Terminology Used in This Notice**

The term "our affiliates" refers to any one or more of FFC and its banking and non-banking affiliates (companies related to FFC by common ownership or control). The terms "we," "our" and "us" refer to each and all of FFC and its affiliates. The terms "you" and "your" refer to individuals who have a relationship with one or more of us. The term "nonpublic personal information" refers to nonpublic information about you that we obtain in connection with providing a financial product or service to you. For example, nonpublic personal information includes information regarding your account balance, payment history and overdraft history. The term "nonaffiliated third parties" refers to companies, other than our affiliates, that we do not own or control. 

**Privacy Notices**

Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read the privacy notices listed below and our Frequently Asked Questions about Privacy Notices to understand what we do.

  * Privacy Notice for Fulton Financial Advisors
  * Privacy Notice for all other Fulton Financial Corporation Banking Affiliates
    * The Columbia Bank
    * Fulton Bank, N.A.
    * Fulton Bank of New Jersey
    * FNB Bank, N.A.
    * Lafayette Ambassador Bank
    * Swineford National Bank

**Why We Collect Information About You**

We collect and use information about you only where we reasonably believe the information will be necessary or useful in providing you with the products and services you request from us, as well as to help us identify new opportunities to provide products, services and information to help you achieve financial success. The information we collect and use about you helps us to maintain the security of your accounts with us, improve the customer service we provide you, and operate more efficiently. 

**How We Protect the Information We Collect**

We take great care to safeguard the information we collect and use about you. We permit access to the nonpublic personal information we collect about you to only those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard your nonpublic personal information. 

**Categories of Information We Collect**

We collect nonpublic personal information about you from the following sources:

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms;
  * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates or others;and 
  * Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency. 

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technology**

We respect the privacy of our customers and are committed to protecting your information on our Web sites with the same care we utilize for all our affiliates' transactions. Our affiliates do not automatically collect personal information from visitors to their Web sites. 

Our affiliates do use online tracking technologies, such as cookies or click stream auditing, for our own internal uses, such as to monitor and maintain information about your visits to our sites, to help us identify and address problems, to improve our sites, to analyze web traffic trends, and to help protect the security and integrity of our sites. Our affiliates may also use online tracking technologies to recommend products and services. 

  * Cookies are small pieces of information that a Web site stores on a visitor's Web browser to remind the site about the visitor the next time they visit the sites. Our affiliates do not store confidential or sensitive information in cookies. Our affiliates use cookies to enhance our customers' online banking session by providing important security features.

Cookies are used within the online banking login process to identify a user's computer to better enhance security. If a cookie is not on the computer or the user changes computers, the use will be asked to re-authenticate. This process helps add an additional level of security for our customers.

Cookies cannot be used to capture your e-mail address, obtain data from your hard drive, or gain confidential or sensitive information about you. Additionally, cookies cannot be read by a Web site other than the one that set the cookie. Some Web sites, however, use cookies to obtain information from your browser. You can set your browser to notify you before accepting a cookie, so that you can control whether you accept or reject a cookie. If you do not accept cookies, your experience at our Web sites may be impacted.

  * Click stream auditing is the process of collecting and analyzing information such as a web surfer's IP address, web pages which referred a web surfer to our Web site, date and time, domain type, and when a web surfer has responded to an advertisement.
  * We may also use pixel tags (also known as "clear gifs," "Web beacons" or "1-by-1gifs") on our sites. These may be used in connection with certain pages of our sites or with email messages to measure the effectiveness of our communications and our marketing campaigns, to compile statistics about usage and response rates, and to assist us in resolving issues that may arise on our sites.
  * We use third party advertising and media companies to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet and to help manage and optimize our Internet business and communications. These networks use both cookie and pixel tag technology to measure the effectiveness of ads for their clients, none of which contain personally-identifiable information, during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide information about goods and services that may be of particular interest to you. We limit these networks from using the information collected by these cookies and pixel tags for any purpose other than to assist us in our advertising efforts. From time to time, we may also share anonymous information with such third party companies in an aggregate form, for purposes of analysis and improvement of our Web site.

_We have adopted the use of the Advertising Options Icon on all targeted ads. Click on the displayed Icon to receive more information and then opt-out or visit the advertising network's website to opt-out._

_You may also opt out of receiving targeted ads from many websites by opting out of network advertising program. One such opt out program is available through the Network Advertising Initiative's Opt Out Tool. Please note that if you opt out, you may still receive online advertising from us or other online advertising networks. Opting out from a specific advertising network means only that the ads you do receive online will be generic and not based on your preferences or behavior._

**Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)**

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) was passed to give parents increased control over what information is collected from their children online and how such information is used. The law applies to websites and services directed to, and which knowingly collect information from, children under the age of 13. Fulton Financial Corporation respects the online privacy of children. Our websites and online services are not directed at children under the age of 13, nor do we knowingly collect, maintain, or use personally identifiable information from them. For more information on COPPA, visit http://www.ftc.gov. 

**Categories of Affiliates to Whom We Disclose Information**

We may disclose nonpublic personal information about you to the following types of our affiliates: 

  * Financial service providers, such as mortgage bankers, securities broker-dealers and insurance agents. 

**Categories of Information We Disclose to Affiliates**

We may disclose the following kinds of nonpublic personal information about you to our affiliates: 

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms, such as your name, address and social security number, and information we may receive from you in connection with credit, investment and insurance products, such as your assets and income;
  * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates or others, such as the types of accounts you have with us, your account balance, payment history, parties to the transaction and credit card usage; and
  * Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency, such as your creditworthiness and credit history.

We disclose this information to our affiliates for a number of reasons, such as to assist us in administering your accounts or to identify products or services our affiliates may offer that may be of interest to you. Our affiliates observe the same practices we do to protect the privacy of information about you.

**Your Rights Concerning Certain Information We Disclose to Our Affiliates**

We are permitted by law to share information about our experiences and transactions with you (such as your account balance and your payment history with us) with our affiliates. We may also share "additional information" about you (such as information we receive from you on applications or from credit reporting agencies) with our affiliates. You may direct us not to disclose this additional information to our affiliates (see **How To Opt** out below.) Even if you opt out, we are allowed by law to share our experiences and transactions with you with our affiliates. 

**How Our Affiliates Use Information to Market to You**

Our affiliates may use all of the nonpublic personal information we disclose to them about you to market their products and services to you. 

**Your Right To Limit Marketing**

You may direct us not to allow our affiliates to use your nonpublic personal information to market their products or services (see **How To Opt Out** below). Your choice to stop marketing from our affiliates will apply until you tell us to change your choice. 

**How to Opt Out**

You may direct us not to disclose additional information about you to our affiliates and not to allow our affiliates to use your nonpublic personal information that we disclose to them to market their products or services to you by filling out a privacy notice, which can be obtained from a branch, and mailing it to us, or by clicking on the link below and filling out the form: 

<http://www.fult.com/privacyoptout>   

Your opt-out will apply to all FFC affiliates with whom you do business. In other words, if you have an account with more than one of our affiliates, you do not need to opt out for each one separately.

**Joint Accounts**

If you have a joint account, and any joint accountholder directs us not to disclose information and/or not to allow affiliates to use your nonpublic personal information to market, that direction will apply to all joint accountholders. 

**Categories of Certain Nonaffiliated Third Parties to Whom We Disclose Information and the Categories of Information We Disclose**

We may disclose nonpublic personal information about you to certain nonaffiliated third parties that perform services or functions on our behalf, such as financial data processing companies that process and maintain your account records for us, or to financial institutions with whom we have written agreements to jointly offer, endorse or sponsor a financial product or service, such as securities brokerage or insurance services.

We may disclose the following nonpublic personal information about you to those nonaffiliated third parties mentioned above: 

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms, such as your name, address and social security number, and information we may receive from you in connection with credit, investment and insurance products, such as your assets and income; 
  * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates or others, such as the types of accounts you have with us, your account balance, payment history, parties to the transaction and credit card usage; and
  * Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency, such as your creditworthiness and credit history. 

When we disclose nonpublic personal information about you under these circumstances, we require that the nonaffiliated third party agree not to disclose the information, or to use the information for any other purpose. 

Other than as described in this section, we do not disclose any nonpublic personal information about you to any nonaffiliated third parties, except as permitted by law. We do not disclose or sell nonpublic personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties for the purpose of marketing non-financial products or services. 

**Information Concerning Former and Inactive Customers**

If you happen to close your account(s) with us at some point in time, or if you become an inactive customer, we will adhere to the privacy policies and practices as described in this Notice.
